Guide to the Hunter Reynolds Papers and Collection MSS.319
Fales Library and Special Collections
Hunter Reynolds Papers and Collection
1980-2007
1993-2007
Fales Library and Special Collections
Reynolds, Hunter, 1959-2022
MSS.319
15 Linear Feet in 8 boxes
The Hunter Reynolds Papers and Collection comprise consists of source material, photographs, videotapes, sketches, press, and correspondence created and received by visual and performance artist and AIDS activist Hunter Reynolds. The processed portion of the collection is material related to Reynolds' Memorial Dress Project, which commemorates individual victims of the AIDS pandemic.
Arrangement
The Hunter Reynolds Papers and Collection are subdivided into series organized by project and media-type.
The Memorial Dress and Book project (Series I, Subseries A and B) collects the material related to Reynolds' Memorial Dress project; it is arranged in alphabetical order between 4 boxes of printed material, 3 objects, and 1 oversized container. Series II includes the test fabrics for the Memorial Dress and the Memorial Dress. Oversize Series I includes two poster tubes containing the Memorial Dress plastic name templates.
Biographical Note
Hunter Reynolds is a visual and performance artist and AIDS activist. An early member of ACT UP, in 1989 Reynolds co-founded Art Positive, an affinity group of ACT-UP to fight homophobia and censorship in the arts. Reynolds' performance, photography, and installations address his experience as an HIV-positive gay man living in the age of AIDS; the work speaks to issues of gender identity, political, social, and sexual histories, mourning and loss, survival, hope and healing. Among his projects are Patina du Prey's Memorial Dress, The Drag Pose Series, Blood Spot Series and Mummification Series. He has collaborated on major performance projects including The Banquet with Chrysanne Stathacos and I-Dea The Goddess with Maxine Heneryson.
Source: Visual AIDS (https://www.visualaids.org/artists/detail/hunter-reynolds)
Conditions Governing Access
Series I and associated objects in Series II are open to researchers. The rest of the collection is unprocessed. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Scope and Content
The Hunter Reynolds Papers and Collection consists of source material, photographs, videotapes, sketches, artworks, press, and correspondence created and received by artist and AIDS activist Hunter Reynolds. The processed portion of the collection is material related to Reynolds' Memorial Dress Project, which commemorates individual victims of the AIDS pandemic.
Provenance
The collection was acquired by NYU's Fales Library & Special Collections from Hunter Reynolds in June 2011.
Appraisal
In May 2019, 29 boxes of unprocessed material, containing mostly clothing, were returned to Hunter Reynolds.
Dress accessories.; Performance artists.; Performance art -- New York (State) -- New York -- Exhibitions.; Art -- Exhibitions.; AIDS activists.; AIDS (Disease) and art -- United States.; Reynolds, Hunter, 1959-2022
- Series I: Memorial Dress
  Arrangement
  The Series is divided into two subseries, documenting the production phase and the exhibition phase of the dress and its accompanying materials. Folders are arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Content
  Series I documents Hunter Reynolds' Memorial Dress project, spanning the years 1992-2010. The series includes material related to the construction and exhibition of his Memorial Dress -- a black ball gown silk-screened with the names of 25,000 people who died of AIDS. Exhibitions of the dress were modeled by Reynolds in character as his alter ego, Patina du Prey. The Memorial Dress was premiered in 1992 at the ICA of Boston, was presented during the 25th anniversary of the Stonewall riots, and produced in collaboration with The Contemporary Art Institute of New York. The material documents the conception and exhibition of the Memorial Dress in the U.S. and internationally, and includes press, production material, exhibition files, and the dress itself.
  - Subseries A: Memorial Dress and Book production
    - Art in America - Memorial Dress Picture, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Artists Space Memorial Book and Transcriptions, 1993-2007 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Comment Book (Photocopies) Berlin, Germany NGBK, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Memorial Books Bound [1 of 3], undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Memorial Books Bound [2 of 3], undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Memorial Books Bound [3 of 3], undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Memorial Book Loose Pages, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Memorial Book - Name Transcriptions [1 of 2], undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Memorial Book - Name Transcriptions [2 of 2], undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Memorial Book - Names Transcribed, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Book - Original Center for the Arts Yerba Buena Gardens, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Memorial Book - Original Buch 1 - Kassel, 1997; Parsons 2001, 1997; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Memorial Book - Original Buch 2 - Boston 1996; Berlin 1997; Parschs 2001, 1996; 1997; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Memorial Book - Original Buch 3 - Parsons Dec.1, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Memorial Book - Original Buch 4 - Parons, Dec. 1, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Memorial Book - Original Buch 5 - Judson 2010; DWA 2000; Parsons 2001, 2010; 2000; 2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Memorial Book Pages, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Memorial Book Photocopies, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Book Production, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Ray Navarro - Inspiration From Death Bed, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Memorial Book Plaque, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Memorial Book Spiral Bound, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Memorial Book - Transcriptions Buch 5 & Sheets, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Memorial Dress - Adding of the Names, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Memorial Dress - Book Drafts, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Memorial Dress - Exhibition/Performance Plaques, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Memorial Dress - Fundraising Letters, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Memorial Dress - Misc., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Memorial Dress - Names Lists [1 of 2], undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Memorial Dress - Names Lists [2 of 2], undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Memorial Dress - Press, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Memorial Dress - Programs and Cards - German, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Memorial Dress - Promotional Cards, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Memorial Quilt Book - Names, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Patina Du Prey's Memorial Dress Comment Book - Dress Codes (Unbound), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Patina Du Prey's Memorial Dress - Press, 1993-2007 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: Memorial Dress and Book Exhibitions
    - [AIDS Projekte - German Brochure], 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Artists Space, March 2007 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Artists Space, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Artists Space - Left Wall, Timeline, Memorial Book Pages, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Artists Space - Right Wall - Name LIst, Photos [1 of 2], undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Artists Space - Right Wall - Name List, Photos [2 of 2], undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Artists Space - Statements & Press Releases, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Artists Space - Translations from German to English, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Campion, Edmund - "Music to Turn On", 1993; 2006; 2007 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - Gupta, Sunil, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - Henryson, Maxine, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Creative Time - Simon Watson, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Dead from AIDS" Correspondence, 1987-1991; 2004 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Di Raimondo, Gia [Ask Hunter?], 1980-1986 [?] (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Documenta Kassel, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Getting to Know You - Reading of the Names, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Hagen, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Hamburg, Leuchtfeur, June 9, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - ICA Boston, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Karl Ernst Osthaus Museum - Hagen - Thema AIDS, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - The Life Ball, Vienna, Austria, May 6, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - [loose papers, Memorial Book?], undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Love AIDS Riot Sex - Catalog - NGBK, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Love AIDS Riot Sex - Programs etc., undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Mary Goldman Gallery - "The Moon Over Gerhard", 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Memorial Dress to File, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Memorial Dress Performance - Berlin, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Mensch, William, 1989-1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Neher, Krista, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Survival AIDS/David Wojnarowicz Rimbaud Series - Catalog PPOW, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Traveling Exhibition, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Trinitatiskirche - Koln - Catalogs, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Trinitatiskirche Koln - Exhibit, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Trinitatiskirche Koln - Exhibition Book, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Trinitatiskirche Koln - Photos Copies, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Yerba Buena Center for the Arts, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Subseries C: Memorial Dress Sound and Video Recordings
    - Hunter Reynolds - Patina du Prey's Memorial Dress - ICA/ Boston, 1993; ID: 319.0001 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0001, Box Shared Fales 134, Dvd 319.0001)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Access DVD available.
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Original format: 3/4" Umatic
      Duration: 4 minutes
    - Patina du Prey's Memorial Dress - Master 1 "Dump tape", 1993; ID: 319.0002 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0002, Box Shared Fales 134, Dvd 319.0002)
      Duration: 20 minutes.
    - Patina du Prey's Memorial Dress - Master 2 "Dump tape", 1993; ID: 319.0003 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0003, Box Shared Fales 134, Dvd 319.0003)
    - Patina du Prey's Memorial Dress - Compilation Master, 1990-1993; ID: 319.0004 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0004)
      1. 2. The Banquet. Duration: 3 minutes 40 seconds 3. The Memorial Dress. Duration: 4 minutes
      Duration: Unknown
    - Patina du Prey's Memorial Dress - Kunst-Werke, Berlin, 1995; ID: 319.0005 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0005)
      General
      Per tape annotaion: Copy von SVHS. Copyright: Karen Fischer
      Original format: VHS
      Duration: 15 minutes
    - Patina du Prey's Memorial Dress - possibly Kunst-Werke, Berlin, ID: 319.0006 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0006)
      Duration: 13 minutes
    - Hunter Reynolds - Patina du Prey's Memorial Dress - Performance, circa 1993; ID: 319.0008 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0008, Box Shared Fales 134, Dvd 319.0008)
      Original format: HI-8
      Duration: 6 minutes.
    - Unidentified, Circa 1990s
      Original format: Video 8mm
    - Life Ball, 1995; ID: 319.0009 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0009)
      Standard: May be PAL
    - Reading of NAMES - Getting to Know You, ID: 319.0010 (Box 9, Media ID: 319.0010)
      Original format: 1/4" audiocassette
- Series II: Objects
  - Subseries A: Memorial Dress
    - Memorial Dress gloves, undated
    - Memorial Dress - Test Fabrics [1 of 2], 1993-1996; cuid6043; 1 item multiple pieces of fabric (Box 103)
      Costume components.
    - Memorial Dress - Test Fabrics [2 of 2], 1993; cuid6044; 1 item one dress (Box 104)
    - Crinoline petticoat, Undated; cuid6045; 1 item one petticoat (Box 112)
    - Black crepeline tulle skirt, Undated; cuid6046; 1 item one skirt (Item MSS.319.cuid6046)
    - White crepeline tulle skirt, Undated; cuid6047; 1 item one skirt (Item MSS.319.cuid6047)
- Oversize Series I: Memorial Dress
  - Memorial Dress - 19 Plastic Templates for Names, undated (Box 7)
  - Memorial Dress - Paper and Plastic Templates, undated (Box 8)